SAI KIRAN BOGA

+91 7416343790

▼ Tarnaka, TG 500007

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Respectful self-motivator gifted at finding reliable solutions for software issues. Experienced in Web development and AR development and offering skills in Reactjs and ThreeJS. Fluent in Javascript and accustomed to working with cross-cultural, global teams.

SKILLS

- HTML 5, CSS3
- JavaScript
- JavaScript frameworks/libraries (ReactJS, ThreeJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Vue.js, AJAX)
- Redux
- WebGL
- AWS deployments
- Jenkins
- Accessibility
- · PHP (Laravel)
- Material UI
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL

WORKSHOPS ON

- Deployment
- Cloud Concepts
- AR/VR
- Three.js

EDUCATION

St. Mary's Group of Institutions Hyderabad • 05/2015

Bachelor of Technology: Electronics And Communication Engineering

LINKS

- https://saiviru.in
- https://github.com/saiviru
- https://bold.pro/my/saiviru

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Organized ethical Hacking workshop conducted by IIT Delhi and addressed more than 100 students
- Java level 1 certification from CCA

WORK HISTORY

Sagarsoft - Senior Software Developer

Hyderabad, India • 06/2023 - Current

Sagarsoft is a product and service-based company that works with elite clients and is a great place to work.

- Worked with Walmart on their internal Stride project, delivering high-quality code on time, effectively managing project timelines, and prioritizing tasks to ensure successful outcomes
- Mentored junior developers, providing guidance on best practices and coding techniques for improved productivity.

Deque Software - Software Developer

Hyderabad, India • 04/2022 - 04/2023

Deque is an accessibility expert company and is committed to the mission of digital equality.

- Specialized in ReactJS and Accessibility. Expertise in delivering exceptional user experiences while adhering to WCAG guidelines. Recognized for showing a can-do attitude and delivering output.
- Strong understanding and application of accessibility on Deque products, to be accessible to everyone by using HTM, JavaScript, CSS, AJAX, and Jenkins
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.

PlugXR - Frontend Developer

Hyderabad, India • 10/2019 - 03/2022

PlugXR is a Cloud-based Augmented Reality platform, a ready drag n drop tool for everyone.

- Managed development of WebAR module and was responsible for implementing market-ready features, using technologies including ReactJS, Redux, and ThreeJS, a Javascript 3D framework, and HTML, CSS, AJAX.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions including deployment using Jenkins and roles to generate project results and meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Integral part of team in setting development standards and scheduling sprints and product releases for the team in setting development standards and scheduling sprints and product releases for the product to stay ahead in the market.

Gloobert - Web Developer

Hyderabad, India • 06/2018 - 08/2019

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, and JSON coding.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS and jQuery languages/libraries..

